Luis Herrera



1209@holbertonschool.com



linkedin.com/in/lh1008



https://lh1008.github.io/

Summary

Cryptocurrency privacy-focused Monero (XMR) enthusiast. Focused in open-source software GNU/Linux operating systems since 2016.

Studied Software Engineering foundations at Holberton School Colombia with a high passion for blockchain technology. Entrepreneur, adventurer, and eager to develop code for our world.

Experience in C, Python, and JavaScript programming languages, hand-coded HTML and CSS with MySQL database integration.

Experience



Software Engineer

Blockchain Labb

Sep 2020 - Present (1 year +)

- Development Coordinator: organize and coordinate development working directly with the developers. Following the company's needs and blockchain integrations.
- Code Reviewer: check the developer's code and make the tryouts.
- Repository and Server Maintainer: maintain, review, and check repository's commits and accept changes. SysOps/DevOps server maintainer.
- Programming Languages: Vuejs, Nuxtjs, Nodejs.

Communication Work-group Coordinator

Monero

Jul 2018 - Present (3 years 2 months +)

- Workgroup communication coordinator.
- Project task management coordinator.
- Junior SysOps/DevOps maintainer.

Software Engineer

Rappi

May 2020 - Jun 2020 (2 months)

- Backend Developer: developed an API to connect the database with the front-end.
- Programming Languages: Python, HTML, CSS
- Database Management: MySQL
- Systema File Management: Git, GitHub
- Task App Management: Trello

Database Analyst

EMCALI - Telecomunicaciones

Sep 2016 - Feb 2018 (1 year 6 months)

- Database Analyst: Microsoft Excel.
- GIS (Geographic Information System) Analyst: GEOVISOR/MapInfo software
- Recruiter: assistant training.
- Software: OPEN-SmartFlex utility software.

Business Development Administrator

Productos Vrinda

Feb 2013 - May 2016 (3 years 4 months)

- Production and service manager.
- Customer Service Representative.
- Sales.

Education

Holberton School

Software Engineer, Programming

2019 - 2021

Foundations - Full Stack Developer

- Programming Languages: C, Python, Javascript
- Web Stack Development: HTML, CSS, Nginx, HaProxy
- Database Management: MySQL
- Application, programs, software: Git, Github, Docker

Specialization - Low Level & Algorithms

- Programming Languages: C, Python, Assembly (libASM)

Udemy Academy

Web Designer, Web Development

2017 - 2018

Web Development Languages: HTML, CSS

Licenses & Certifications

EF SET Certificate - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

C1 ADVANCED

EF SET English Certificate 94/100 (C1 Advanced) - EF Standard English Test (EF SET)

Skills

English • Open Source Software • Software Development • Business Strategy • Project Management
MySQL • JavaScript • C (Programming Language) • Python (Programming Language)